Authors	Author(s) ID	Title	Year	Source title	Volume	Issue	Art. No.	Page start	Page end	Page count	Cited by	DOI	Link	Affiliations	Authors with affiliations	Abstract	Author Keywords	Index Keywords	Document Type	Publication Stage	Open Access	Source	EID
"Virga P., Duygulu P."	55989971300;23134573600;	Systematic evaluation of machine translation methods for image and video annotation	2005	Lecture Notes in Computer Science	3568			174	183		4	10.1007/11526346_21	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-26444472411&doi=10.1007%2f11526346_21&partnerID=40&md5=1297636e6511d91f15bdce4fdd578188	"Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, United States; Department of Computer Engineering, Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey"	"Virga, P., Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, United States; Duygulu, P., Department of Computer Engineering, Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey"	"In this study, we present a systematic evaluation of machine translation methods applied to the image annotation problem. We used the well-studied Corel data set and the broadcast news videos used by TRECVID 2003 as our dataset. We experimented with different models of machine translation with different parameters. The results showed that the simplest model produces the best performance. Based on this experience, we also proposed a new method, based on cross-lingual information retrieval techniques, and obtained a better retrieval performance. © Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg 2005."		Mathematical models; Problem solving; Cross-lingual information retrieval; Image annotation; Machine translation methods; Image retrieval	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-26444472411
"Zens R., Hasan S., Ney H."	18042581600;56051024000;7006360226;	A systematic comparison of training criteria for statistical machine translation	2007	EMNLP-CoNLL 2007 - Proceedings of the 2007 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning				524	532		12		https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-78650170616&partnerID=40&md5=0ca0a2e1ae8d38cbbf472d6c8a74bd7c	"Computer Science Department, RWTH Aachen University, D-52056 Aachen, Germany"	"Zens, R., Computer Science Department, RWTH Aachen University, D-52056 Aachen, Germany; Hasan, S., Computer Science Department, RWTH Aachen University, D-52056 Aachen, Germany; Ney, H., Computer Science Department, RWTH Aachen University, D-52056 Aachen, Germany"	"We address the problem of training the free parameters of a statistical machine translation system. We show significant improvements over a state-of-the-art minimum error rate training baseline on a large Chinese-English translation task. We present novel training criteria based on maximum likelihood estimation and expected loss computation. Additionally, we compare the maximum a-posteriori decision rule and the minimum Bayes risk decision rule. We show that, not only from a theoretical point of view but also in terms of translation quality, the minimum Bayes risk decision rule is preferable. © 2007 Association for Computational Linguistics."		Decision rules; Free parameters; Maximum a posteriori; Minimum bayes risk; Minimum error rate; Statistical machine translation; Statistical machine translation system; Theoretical points; Translation quality; Computational linguistics; Information theory; Maximum likelihood estimation; Natural language processing systems; Translation (languages)	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-78650170616
"Oliveira F., Wong F., Dong M.-C."	9737372800;9738198000;9633769000;	Systematic noun phrase chunking by parsing constraint synchronous grammar in application to Portuguese Chinese machine translation	2009	"6th International Conference on Information Technology and Applications, ICITA 2009"				292	295		2		https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-77954013326&partnerID=40&md5=9eb43d3ec43013ccefeec491ad93644f	"Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Macau"	"Oliveira, F., Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Macau; Wong, F., Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Macau; Dong, M.-C., Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Macau"	"Due to the inherent ambiguities in natural languages, the parsing of a sentence in any Machine Translation System may generate different ambiguous parse trees, and the categorical constituents of each tree are often nested with each other. Since this phenomenon is unpredictable and difficult to deal with, the parsing of these sentences, especially for long ones, is very easy to get failed when analyzed, and easy to produce poor translations. As a result, a preprocessing module is proposed for systematically chunking Noun Phrases. This paper describes the modeling of Noun Phrases based on Constraint Synchronous Grammar formalism, with emphasis in its application to Portuguese-Chinese Machine Translation. This formalism can model not only syntactic structures of two languages simultaneously, but also express detailed feature structures of the languages. © ICITA 2009."	Constraint synchronous grammar; Machine translation; Noun phrase chunking	Feature structure; Machine translation systems; Machine translations; Natural languages; Noun phrase; Parse trees; Preprocessing modules; Synchronous grammars; Syntactic structure; Formal languages; Information technology; Information theory; Linguistics; Speech transmission; Translation (languages)	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-77954013326
"Oliveira F., Wong F., Hong I.-S."	9737372800;9738198000;36696432500;	Systematic processing of long sentences in rule based Portuguese-Chinese machine translation	2010	Lecture Notes in Computer Science (including subseries Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence and Lecture Notes in Bioinformatics)	6008 LNCS			417	426		3	10.1007/978-3-642-12116-6_35	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-78650438243&doi=10.1007%2f978-3-642-12116-6_35&partnerID=40&md5=193b232c465ff30ae3d2ee18226be8b4	"Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Av. Padre Tomás Pereira, Taipa, Macau"	"Oliveira, F., Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Av. Padre Tomás Pereira, Taipa, Macau; Wong, F., Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Av. Padre Tomás Pereira, Taipa, Macau; Hong, I.-S., Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Macau, Av. Padre Tomás Pereira, Taipa, Macau"	"The translation quality and parsing efficiency are often disappointed when Rule based Machine Translation systems deal with long sentences. Due to the complicated syntactic structure of the language, many ambiguous parse trees can be generated during the translation process, and it is not easy to select the most suitable parse tree for generating the correct translation. This paper presents an approach to parse and translate long sentences efficiently in application to Rule based Portuguese-Chinese Machine Translation. A systematic approach to break down the length of the sentences based on patterns, clauses, conjunctions, and punctuation is considered to improve the performance of the parsing analysis. On the other hand, Constraint Synchronous Grammar is used to model both source and target languages simultaneously at the parsing stage to further reduce ambiguities and the parsing efficiency. © Springer-Verlag 2010."	Constraint synchronous grammar; Rule based machine translation; Sentence partitioning	Break down; Machine translation systems; Machine translations; Parse trees; Rule based; Sentence partitioning; Synchronous grammars; Syntactic structure; Target language; Translation process; Translation quality; Computational linguistics; Formal languages; Information theory; Text processing; Word processing; Translation (languages)	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-78650438243
"Samad Zadeh Kaljahi R., Rubino R., Roturier J., Foster J."	57191646291;37007663100;55039583500;23090701700;	A detailed analysis of phrase-based and syntax-based machine translation: The search for systematic differences	2012	AMTA 2012 - Proceedings of the 10th Conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas									https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-84992416892&partnerID=40&md5=c095663eb132948c39a17d94698706b1	"NCLT, School of Computing, Dublin City University, Dublin 9, Ireland; Symantec Research Labs, Ballycoolin Business Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland"	"Samad Zadeh Kaljahi, R., NCLT, School of Computing, Dublin City University, Dublin 9, Ireland, Symantec Research Labs, Ballycoolin Business Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland; Rubino, R., NCLT, School of Computing, Dublin City University, Dublin 9, Ireland, Symantec Research Labs, Ballycoolin Business Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland; Roturier, J., Symantec Research Labs, Ballycoolin Business Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland; Foster, J., NCLT, School of Computing, Dublin City University, Dublin 9, Ireland"	"This paper describes a range of automatic and manual comparisons of phrase-based and syntax-based statistical machine translation methods applied to English-German and English-French translation of user-generated content. The syntax-based methods underperform the phrase-based models and the relaxation of syntactic constraints to broaden translation rule coverage means that these models do not necessarily generate output which is more grammatical than the output produced by the phrase-based models. Although the systems generate different output and can potentially be fruitfully combined, the lack of systematic difference between these models makes the combination task more challenging."		Computational linguistics; Syntactics; Machine translations; Phrase-based models; Statistical machine translation; Translation rules; User-generated content; Computer aided language translation	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-84992416892
"Gimpel K., Batra D., Dyer C., Shakhnarovich G."	51665019100;24764919500;51664869700;6507166713;	A systematic exploration of diversity in machine translation	2013	"EMNLP 2013 - 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, Proceedings of the Conference"				1100	1111		34		https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-84926335585&partnerID=40&md5=39e100679be5e5f3d486c87b02b5923f	"Toyota Technological Institute at Chicago, Chicago, IL  60637, United States; Virginia Tech., Blacksburg, VA  24061, United States; Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA  15213, United States"	"Gimpel, K., Toyota Technological Institute at Chicago, Chicago, IL  60637, United States; Batra, D., Virginia Tech., Blacksburg, VA  24061, United States; Dyer, C., Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA  15213, United States; Shakhnarovich, G., Toyota Technological Institute at Chicago, Chicago, IL  60637, United States"	"This paper addresses the problem of producing a diverse set of plausible translations. We present a simple procedure that can be used with any statistical machine translation (MT) system. We explore three ways of using diverse translations: (1) system combination, (2) discriminative reranking with rich features, and (3) a novel post-editing scenario in which multiple translations are presented to users. We find that diversity can improve performance on these tasks, especially for sentences that are difficult for MT. © 2013 Association for Computational Linguistics."		Computational linguistics; Computer aided language translation; Discriminative reranking; Improve performance; Machine translations; Post-editing; Rich features; Statistical machine translation; System combination; Systematic exploration; Natural language processing systems	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-84926335585
"Zbib R., Markiewicz G., Matsoukas S., Schwartz R., Makhoul J."	6507259855;55329400800;6507112233;7404170783;7007128199;	Systematic comparison of professional and crowdsourced reference translations for machine translation	2013	"NAACL HLT 2013 - 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, Proceedings of the Main Conference"				612	616		8		https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-84926194113&partnerID=40&md5=1f68a2a8bc8a9f35ce6a759bc42a1f50	"Raytheon BBN Technologies, Cambridge, MA  02138, United States"	"Zbib, R., Raytheon BBN Technologies, Cambridge, MA  02138, United States; Markiewicz, G., Raytheon BBN Technologies, Cambridge, MA  02138, United States; Matsoukas, S., Raytheon BBN Technologies, Cambridge, MA  02138, United States; Schwartz, R., Raytheon BBN Technologies, Cambridge, MA  02138, United States; Makhoul, J., Raytheon BBN Technologies, Cambridge, MA  02138, United States"	"We present a systematic study of the effect of crowdsourced translations on Machine Translation performance. We compare Machine Translation systems trained on the same data but with translations obtained using Amazon's Mechanical Turk vs. professional translations, and show that the same performance is obtained from Mechanical Turk translations at 1/5th the cost. We also show that adding a Mechanical Turk reference translation of the development set improves parameter tuning and output evaluation. © 2013 Association for Computational Linguistics."		Computational linguistics; Computer aided language translation; Amazon's mechanical turks; Machine translation systems; Machine translations; Mechanical turks; On-machines; Parameter-tuning; Systematic study; Translation (languages)	Conference Paper	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-84926194113
"El Maazouzi Z., El Mohajir B.E., Al Achhab M."	57193028612;7801344901;13002734100;	A systematic reading in statistical translation: From the statistical machine translation to the neural translation models	2017	Journal of Information and Communication Technology	16	2		408	441		1		https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85029566000&partnerID=40&md5=a241d1dd860e2ef60486c16425b8c924	"N2T Laboratory, National School of Applied Sciences, University Abdelmalek Essaadi, Morocco"	"El Maazouzi, Z., N2T Laboratory, National School of Applied Sciences, University Abdelmalek Essaadi, Morocco; El Mohajir, B.E., N2T Laboratory, National School of Applied Sciences, University Abdelmalek Essaadi, Morocco; Al Achhab, M., N2T Laboratory, National School of Applied Sciences, University Abdelmalek Essaadi, Morocco"	"Achieving high accuracy in automatic translation tasks has been one of the challenging goals for researchers in the area of machine translation since decades. Thus, the eagerness of exploring new possible ways to improve machine translation was always the matter for researchers in the field. Automatic translation as a key application in the natural language processing domain has developed many approaches, namely statistical machine translation and recently neural machine translation that improved largely the translation quality especially for Latin languages. They have even made it possible for the translation of some language pairs to approach human translation quality. In this paper, we present a survey of the state of the art of statistical translation, where we describe the different existing methodologies, and we overview the recent research studies while pointing out the main strengths and limitations of the different approaches."	Natural language processing; Neural language model; Neural networks; Recurrent neural networks		Article	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-85029566000
"Grandy C.A., Donnan J.R., Peddle J.T., Romme K., Kim S., Gamble J.-M."	57197861960;16033195300;57113767400;57204293455;57204284418;55822965127;	A systematic assessment of the availability and clinical drug information coverage of machine-readable clinical drug data sources for building knowledge translation products	2018	Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association	25	9		1240	1247			10.1093/jamia/ocy074	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85055131397&doi=10.1093%2fjamia%2focy074&partnerID=40&md5=5bc582f82092d28fc5bc14970e3c77e2	"School of Pharmacy, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, Canada; Health Sciences Library, Memorial University of Newfoundland, Canada; School of Pharmacy, Faculty of Science, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada"	"Grandy, C.A., School of Pharmacy, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, Canada; Donnan, J.R., School of Pharmacy, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, Canada; Peddle, J.T., School of Pharmacy, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, Canada; Romme, K., Health Sciences Library, Memorial University of Newfoundland, Canada; Kim, S., School of Pharmacy, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, Canada; Gamble, J.-M., School of Pharmacy, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, Canada, School of Pharmacy, Faculty of Science, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada"	"Objective: To identify and describe clinical drug data sources that have the potential to serve as a repository of information for developing drug knowledge translation products. Methods: Two reviewers independently screened citations from PubMed and Embase, websites from the web search engine Google, and references from selected journals. Publicly licensed or non-proprietary data sources containing clinical drug information accessible in a machine-readable format were eligible. Data sources were assessed for their coverage across 18 pre-specified domains and 74 elements of clinical drug information. Results: Of the 3369 unique citations or webpages screened, 44 drug information data sources were identified. Of these, 22 data sources met the study inclusion criteria. There was a mean of 4.5 (SD=5.19) domains covered by each source and a mean of 10.9 (SD=18) elements covered by each source. None of the data sources covered all domains and eight elements were not addressed by any source. All of the data sources identified by the study are government or academic databases. Conclusion: Our study demonstrated the availability of machine-readable clinical drug data that could help facilitate the creation of novel drug knowledge translation products. However, we identified clinical content gaps in the available non-proprietary drug information sources. Further evaluation of the quality of each data source would be necessary prior to incorporating these sources into any knowledge translation products intended for clinical use. © 2018 The Author(s)."	Data Sources; Databases; Information Retrieval; Knowledge Translation; Machine-Readable Data Files	"Article; data analysis; drug information; government; information retrieval; knowledge base; adverse drug reaction; drug interaction; drug therapy; factual database; human; procedures; translational research; drug; Databases, Factual; Drug Interactions; Drug Therapy; Drug-Related Side Effects and Adverse Reactions; Humans; Pharmaceutical Preparations; Translational Medical Research"	Article	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-85055131397
"Dew K.N., Turner A.M., Choi Y.K., Bosold A., Kirchhoff K."	56779814300;35300769400;57193066720;57203114311;57207559745;	Development of machine translation technology for assisting health communication: A systematic review	2018	Journal of Biomedical Informatics	85			56	67		21	10.1016/j.jbi.2018.07.018	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85050539560&doi=10.1016%2fj.jbi.2018.07.018&partnerID=40&md5=1ad9f472fa7f1653b0497ada30a6935c	"University of Washington, Dept. of Human Centered Design & Engineering, Northwest Center for Public Health Practice, 1107 NE 45th Street, Suite 400, Seattle, WA  98105, United States; University of Washington, Dept. of Health Services and Dept. Biomedical Informatics and Medical Education, Northwest Center for Public Health Practice, 1107 NE 45th Street, Suite 400, Seattle, WA  98105, United States; University of Washington, Dept. of Biomedical Informatics and Medical Education, Seattle, WA, United States; University of Washington, Dept. of Health Services, Seattle, WA, United States; University of Washington, Dept. of Electrical Engineering, Seattle, WA, United States"	"Dew, K.N., University of Washington, Dept. of Human Centered Design & Engineering, Northwest Center for Public Health Practice, 1107 NE 45th Street, Suite 400, Seattle, WA  98105, United States; Turner, A.M., University of Washington, Dept. of Health Services and Dept. Biomedical Informatics and Medical Education, Northwest Center for Public Health Practice, 1107 NE 45th Street, Suite 400, Seattle, WA  98105, United States; Choi, Y.K., University of Washington, Dept. of Biomedical Informatics and Medical Education, Seattle, WA, United States; Bosold, A., University of Washington, Dept. of Health Services, Seattle, WA, United States; Kirchhoff, K., University of Washington, Dept. of Electrical Engineering, Seattle, WA, United States"	"Objectives: To (1) characterize how machine translation (MT) is being developed to overcome language barriers in health settings; and (2) based on evaluations presented in the literature, determine which MT approaches show evidence of promise and what steps need to be taken to encourage adoption of MT technologies in health settings. Materials & methods: We performed a systematic literature search covering 2006–2016 in major health, engineering, and computer science databases. After removing duplicates, two levels of screening identified 27 articles for full text review and analysis. Our review and qualitative analysis covered application setting, target users, underlying technology, whether MT was used in isolation or in combination with human editing, languages tested, evaluation methods, findings, and identified gaps. Results: Of 27 studies, a majority focused on MT systems for use in clinical settings (n = 18), and eight of these involved speech-based MT systems for facilitating patient-provider communications. Text-based MT systems (n = 19) aimed at generating a range of multilingual health materials. Almost a third of all studies (n = 8) pointed to MT's potential as a starting point before human input. Studies employed a variety of human and automatic MT evaluation methods. In comparison studies, statistical machine translation (SMT) systems were more accurate than rule-based systems when large corpora were available. For a variety of systems, performance was best for translations of simple, less technical sentences and from English to Western European languages. Only one system has been fully deployed. Conclusions: MT is currently being developed primarily through pilot studies to improve multilingual communication in health settings and to increase access to health resources for a variety of languages. However, continued concerns about accuracy limit the deployment of MT systems in these settings. The variety of piloted systems and the lack of shared evaluation criteria will likely continue to impede adoption in health settings, where excellent accuracy and a strong evidence base are critical. Greater translation accuracy and use of standard evaluation criteria would encourage deployment of MT into health settings. For now, the literature points to using MT in health communication as an initial step to be followed by human correction. © 2018"	Health communication; Health literacy; Natural language processing; Public health; Public health informatics	"Computational linguistics; Natural language processing systems; Public health; Health communication; Health literacy; Machine translations; Multilingual communications; Patient-provider communication; Public health informatics; Standard evaluations; Statistical machine translation; Computer aided language translation; access to information; accuracy; assistive technology; communication software; computer aided design; example based translation; health care access; health education; human; information dissemination; intermethod comparison; language processing; machine translation technology; medical error; medical informatics; medical information; medical information system; multilingualism; priority journal; qualitative analysis; quality control; Review; rule based translation; statistical machine translation system; statistical model; systematic review; translation accuracy; artificial neural network; biology; language; machine learning; medical information; translating (language); Computational Biology; Health Communication; Humans; Language; Machine Learning; Models, Statistical; Neural Networks (Computer); Translating"	Review	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-85050539560
[No author name available]	[No author id available]	Erratum: A systematic assessment of the availability and clinical drug information coverage of machine-readable clinical drug data sources for building knowledge translation products (Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association (2018) DOI: 10.1093/jamia/ocy074)	2019	Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association	26	1		91				10.1093/jamia/ocy141	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85059267149&doi=10.1093%2fjamia%2focy141&partnerID=40&md5=243d9227a2d864f6e9ea72fb5aaf53f6			"Catherine Anne Grandy, Jennifer R Donnan, Justin T Peddle, Kristen Romme, Satpyul Kim and John-Michael Gamble. A systematic assessment of the availability and clinical drug information coverage of machine-readable clinical drug data sources for building knowledge translation products. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2018; doi: 10.1093/jamia/ocy074. In Grandy et al., Volume 25, Issue 9 of the Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association, the following changes were made: The last word of the first paragraph with the results section has been changed from ""DrugBank"" to now read ""DrugCentral."" A line under the first row of data in Table 1 has been removed. Additionally, the supplementary file has been updated. These changes have been made to the original article online. © The Author(s) 2018."		erratum; error	Erratum	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-85059267149
"Vázquez R., Raganato A., Creutz M., Tiedemann J."	57217631132;57190841330;14051599200;14833666200;	A systematic study of inner-attention-based sentence representations in multilingual neural machine translation	2020	Computational Linguistics	46	2		387	424		1	10.1162/COLI_a_00377	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85087442247&doi=10.1162%2fCOLI_a_00377&partnerID=40&md5=899c25e816e6b558e2adc640e98ccc56	"University of Helsinki, Department of Digital Humanities, Finland"	"Vázquez, R., University of Helsinki, Department of Digital Humanities, Finland; Raganato, A., University of Helsinki, Department of Digital Humanities, Finland; Creutz, M., University of Helsinki, Department of Digital Humanities, Finland; Tiedemann, J., University of Helsinki, Department of Digital Humanities, Finland"	"Neural machine translation has considerably improved the quality of automatic translations by learning good representations of input sentences. In this article, we explore a multilingual translation model capable of producing fixed-size sentence representations by incorporating an intermediate crosslingual shared layer, which we refer to as attention bridge. This layer exploits the semantics from each language and develops into a language-agnostic meaning representation that can be efficiently used for transfer learning. We systematically study the impact of the size of the attention bridge and the effect of including additional languages in the model. In contrast to related previous work, we demonstrate that there is no conflict between translation performance and the use of sentence representations in downstream tasks. In particular, we show that larger intermediate layers not only improve translation quality, especially for long sentences, but also push the accuracy of trainable classification tasks. Nevertheless, shorter representations lead to increased compression that is beneficial in non-trainable similarity tasks. Similarly, we show that trainable downstream tasks benefit from multilingual models, whereas additional language signals do not improve performance in non-trainable benchmarks. This is an important insight that helps to properly design models for specific applications. Finally, we also include an in-depth analysis of the proposed attention bridge and its ability to encode linguistic properties. We carefully analyze the information that is captured by individual attention heads and identify interesting patterns that explain the performance of specific settings in linguistic probing tasks. © 2020 Association for Computational Linguistics."		Classification (of information); Computational linguistics; Computer aided language translation; Semantics; Transfer learning; Automatic translation; Classification tasks; Improve performance; Intermediate layers; Linguistic properties; Machine translations; Multilingual translations; Translation quality; Benchmarking	Article	Final		Scopus	2-s2.0-85087442247
"Kahlon N.K., Singh W."	57225149656;41662186800;	Machine translation from text to sign language: a systematic review	2021	Universal Access in the Information Society								10.1007/s10209-021-00823-1	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85109324522&doi=10.1007%2fs10209-021-00823-1&partnerID=40&md5=44aa80d0b65646d00bd385df6139a99d	"Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Punjabi University, Patiala, Punjab  147002, India"	"Kahlon, N.K., Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Punjabi University, Patiala, Punjab  147002, India; Singh, W., Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Punjabi University, Patiala, Punjab  147002, India"	"An equal opportunity for all is the basic right of every human being. The deaf society of the world needs to have access to all the information just like hearing people do. For this to happen there should be a mode of direct communication between hearing and deaf people. The need at this time is to automate this communication so as the deaf society is not dependent upon human interpreters. This paper deals with the systematic survey of conventional and state-of-the-art sign language machine translation and sign language generation projects. We used a standard procedure of carrying out a systematic literature review on 148 studies published in 30 reputed journals and 40 premium conferences and workshops. Existing literature about sign language machine translation is broadly classified into three different categories. These categories are further sub-classified into different classifications depending upon the type of machine translation. Studies pertaining to the specified classifications have been presented with their advantages and limitations. Different methods for sign language generation are reported with their benefits and limitations. Manual and automatic evaluation methods used in every study is presented along with their respective performance metrics. We call for increased efforts in presentation of signs to make them an easy and comfortable mode of communication for deaf society. There is also a requirement to improve translation methods and include the contribution of advanced technologies such as deep learning and neural networks to make an optimal translation process between text and sign language. © 2021, The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature."	Deaf people communication; Machine translation; Sign language; Sign language generation; Systematic literature review	Audition; Computational linguistics; Deep learning; Deep neural networks; Advanced technology; Automatic evaluation; Direct communications; Machine translations; Sign language machine translation; Standard procedures; Systematic literature review; Translation process; Computer aided language translation	Article	Article in Press		Scopus	2-s2.0-85109324522
Lee S.-M.	56014829500;	The effectiveness of machine translation in foreign language education: a systematic review and meta-analysis	2021	Computer Assisted Language Learning								10.1080/09588221.2021.1901745	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85104758163&doi=10.1080%2f09588221.2021.1901745&partnerID=40&md5=517aa5f1b819da1a215379bbc19d0d2d	"Kyung Hee University, Yongin, South Korea"	"Lee, S.-M., Kyung Hee University, Yongin, South Korea"	"With a significant number of students using machine translation (MT) for academic purposes in recent years, language teachers can no longer ignore it in their classrooms. Although an increasing number of studies have reported its pedagogical benefits, studies have also revealed that language teachers are still sceptical about using MT for various reasons. Most of all, they have limited trust in MT quality and the effectiveness of using MT in foreign language (FL) learning. Hence, the current study examined these issues to provide an overview and a guide to language teachers regarding the use of MT in FL education. The study examined 87 MT studies related to FL education published between 2000 and 2019. It employed both systematic review (primary) and meta-analysis (secondary) as research methods for a robust data analysis. The results showed that the number of publications in this area has increased in recent years and that MT quality has been significantly enhanced. Most studies also reported the positive impacts of using MT in FL learning, particularly for writing. However, this study also found that students had mixed emotions about MT and that there are disparities in perceptions between instructors and students. Based on the results, the present study presents several pedagogical implications and suggestions for future research on MT. © 2021 Informa UK Limited, trading as Taylor & Francis Group."	Effectiveness; L2 writing; machine translation; meta-analysis		Article	Article in Press		Scopus	2-s2.0-85104758163
Rivera-Trigueros I.	57194711268;	Machine translation systems and quality assessment: a systematic review	2021	Language Resources and Evaluation								10.1007/s10579-021-09537-5	https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85104240751&doi=10.1007%2fs10579-021-09537-5&partnerID=40&md5=0120d93b9368b8a17bd01e6f923e41a4	"Department of Translation and Interpreting, Universidad de Granada, C/Buensuceso, 11, Granada, 18002, Spain"	"Rivera-Trigueros, I., Department of Translation and Interpreting, Universidad de Granada, C/Buensuceso, 11, Granada, 18002, Spain"	"Nowadays, in the globalised context in which we find ourselves, language barriers can still be an obstacle to accessing information. On occasions, it is impossible to satisfy the demand for translation by relying only in human translators, therefore, tools such as Machine Translation (MT) are gaining popularity due to their potential to overcome this problem. Consequently, research in this field is constantly growing and new MT paradigms are emerging. In this paper, a systematic literature review has been carried out in order to identify what MT systems are currently most employed, their architecture, the quality assessment procedures applied to determine how they work, and which of these systems offer the best results. The study is focused on the specialised literature produced by translation experts, linguists, and specialists in related fields that include the English–Spanish language combination. Research findings show that neural MT is the predominant paradigm in the current MT scenario, being Google Translator the most used system. Moreover, most of the analysed works used one type of evaluation—either automatic or human—to assess machine translation and only 22% of the works combined these two types of evaluation. However, more than a half of the works included error classification and analysis, an essential aspect for identifying flaws and improving the performance of MT systems. © 2021, The Author(s)."	Evaluation; Machine translation; Quality; Systematic review		Review	Article in Press		Scopus	2-s2.0-85104240751
